habbo.com 2010-12-31

# Habbo Hotel -

  * [Click here to view our Privacy Policy, Singapore, Malaysia and Philippines residents](http://www.habbo.com/help/136)

Effective Date: June 13, 2008

Privacy Policy

Habbo Hotel is a place where people can create their own Habbos, have fun, hang out, play games, and make friends. Because of its interactive content, Habbo Hotel is for users who are thirteen (13) years of age or older. We urge everyone, especially teens and their parents to use and enjoy our web site responsibly. At Sulake, Inc. (Sulake, Inc. and its parent and its and their affiliates and subsidiaries are collectively " **Sulake** "), we respect your privacy concerns and we understand that visitors to Habbo Hotel need to understand the uses of their Personal Information (defined below). This Privacy Policy details the measures taken by Sulake to protect your privacy in connection with your use of [www.habbo.com](http://www.habbo.com/) (however accessed and/or used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices or otherwise) and other interactive features or downloads that are that are accessible or downloadable through, or related to, [www.habbo.com](http://www.habbo.com/) and owed by Sulake (collectively the " **Site** ") and other sites owned and operated by Sulake that link to this Privacy Policy. Sulake does not intend to collect any Personal Information from children under thirteen (13) years of age, unless Sulake believes such collection to be permitted by law; please read below for Sulake's policy with respect to children under thirteen (13). This Privacy Policy only covers information collected at or via the Site and does not cover any information collected at any other web site or offline by Sulake (unless specifically stated). Please review this Privacy Policy carefully. In addition, please review the Site's [Terms of Use](http://www.habbo.com/papers/termsAndConditions) which govern your use of the Site.

 **Your California Privacy Rights:**

Residents of the State of California, under certain provisions of the California Civil Code, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed Personal Information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that if the company has a privacy policy that gives either an opt-out or opt-in choice for use of your Personal Information by third parties for marketing purposes, the company may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options. Sulake has opted for the alternative option and therefore provides you with the opportunity to opt-out or opt-in to the use of your Personal Information by third parties for direct marketing purposes. Therefore, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of third parties that received your Personal Information for marketing purposes.

 **Privacy Policy Overview:**

This policy statement discloses our privacy practices including the notification of:

* Personal Information collected through the Site;  
* Intended usage of this Personal Information;  
* Choices available regarding opt-in/opt-out, data collection, use and distribution of the Personal Information;  
* Security measures designed to protect the loss or misuse of information under our control; and  
* How to maintain the accuracy of your Personal Information.

 **How Information is Collected and Used:**

 ** _When does Sulake collect Personal Information?_**

The Site may collect personally identifiable information about you, such as your name, e-mail address and phone number (" **Personal Information** ") and other information that, on its own, can not be used to identify you personally, such as your age (" **Demographic Information** "). We may collect the Personal Information and Demographic Information at multiple places on the Site, including, the Site's main registration form; entry forms for contests, sweepstakes, or surveys; or when you submit content or communications to the Site. If we ever use any Demographic Information together with any Personal Information, such Demographic Information will be treated as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

Sulake gathers user information to provide you with a customized experience on the Site. Your user information helps us tailor the content, services, goods and advertising to your current and future needs. For this reason, if you are thirteen (13) years of age or older we will ask you to provide Personal Information when you first sign-up and create your Habbo, visit certain areas of Habbo Hotel, or engage in activities (e.g., download software, enter a contest, order products, or subscribe to a newsletter). If you choose not to register, you may not have access to areas that require personal identification.

We reserve the right to collect and disclose (to our affiliates and to non-affiliate third parties) Demographic and Personal Information to the extent permitted by applicable law, as specifically restricted in this Privacy Policy or in the [Terms of Use](http://www.habbo.com/papers/termsAndConditions). Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Privacy Policy or elsewhere, we reserve the right at all times to disclose any information in connection with a Mandatory Disclosure (defined below) or a Change of Control (defined below).

We encourage you to use caution and common sense in giving out Personal Information when using community services or otherwise. We have no control over third parties to whom you may give Personal Information through the use of our Site or otherwise post on the Site, including on your Public Profile.

 **E-mail/Text Messages:**

If you register with our Site or purchase products from us, from time to time, we may send communications to you with informative messages about our services or third party products and services we believe may be of interest to you, such as new features and services, special offers and updated information. The communications may contain code that enables our database to track your usage of the communication, including whether the communication was opened and/or what links (if any) were clicked. We will combine that information to other information we have about you and may use that information to improve your Site experience and/or provide customized communications to you.

 **Registration:**

When you register, Sulake asks for your e-mail address, a user-selected user name and other information. Once you are a registered user, you can update your profile and may be able to provide additional preferential information. Sulake may also ask for other optional information, including Demographic Information. 

**Submissions:**

Information submitted to the Site through a "contact us" from, address or other similar mechanism, or when you otherwise e-mail us, may not receive a response from Sulake. We will not use this information to contact you for marketing purposes unrelated to your inquiry unless you agree otherwise. For security reasons, we do not recommend that you send non-public Personal Information, such as passwords, social security numbers, or bank account information to us by e-mail or text message.

The Site may make blogs, message boards and other public forums available to its users. If you post Personal Information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public. We also cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose Personal Information in these areas.

Also, remember that if you submit comments, votes, blog entries, text, photographs, videos, music or other user-generated content to the Site, it may be published online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed). Others may have access to this content and may have the ability to share it with third parties across the Internet. Sulake may also publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal Information with the content (or a portion thereof), and Sulake may use the content, (or a portion thereof) for advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. For full terms and conditions regarding user-generated content you submit to the Site, please review the Site's [Terms of Use](http://www.habbo.com/papers/termsAndConditions).

 **Content You Send From The Web Site To A Friend:**

If you send a friend a communication from the Site, the information you provide is used on a one-time basis to facilitate the communication and is not used for any other marketing purpose, unless we obtain additional consent. 

**Third Parties Provide Us With Information About You:**

We also may, from time to time, combine the information we collect from you with information obtained from third parties. We may do this to provide you with services, tailor our content to you or present you with a chance to purchase products or services that may be of interest to you. We may combine information received from third parties with information we collect through the Site. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to any Personal Information received from third parties, unless we tell you otherwise at the time you provide us with your Personal Information.

 **Order Forms and Store:**

Sulake also uses forms for users to request information, products and services. For such forms, we collect a user's contact information (e.g., e-mail address and in the case of delivery of tangible products, delivery address and phone number) and necessary information to process the order (e.g., credit card number and billing address). Contact information from the order is used to send orders to our registered users and to get in touch with the user when deemed necessary. Sulake may use third parties to accept and process orders for merchandise and products, including software, and to operate the Site and such third parties may have access to your Personal Information.

 **Contests, Sweepstakes and Promotions:**

Sulake may occasionally present a special contest, sweepstakes or promotion (" **Promotion** ") that is sponsored by Sulake or another company. To qualify for entry in that Promotion, we may ask you to provide Personal Information. If we plan to share that information with the sponsor(s) or with others, we will provide a statement to that effect in the Promotion terms, and provide you with an ability to opt-in or opt-out of sharing at your Personal Information other then for purposes of operating the Promotion. You may also need to agree to the official rules for a Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion.

 **Non-Personally Identifiable Information - Usage Information:**

We may collect certain non-personally identifiable information related to your usage of the Site and how you arrived at the Site (" **Usage Information** "), which may include a visitor's "IP Address" (discussed below) or another unique identifier for a device used to access the Internet, operating system, browser type, referring web site URL. This Usage Information allows us, among other things, to calculate the number of visitors to the Site, diagnose problems with the Site's server and operate the Site. Usage Information may also be used to tailor and improve the Site, serve you relevant content and/or advertising at the Site and serve you an appropriate version of a web page. 

**IP Address:**

An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to you whenever you access the Internet and is often associated with the place where you enter the Internet like your Internet Service Provider ("ISP"), your company or your university. This IP address may be the same each time you access the Internet or it may change. 

**Cookies:**

A "cookie" is a small line of text that is stored with your Web browser for record-keeping purposes and to help us provide better service to you. Your browser has options to accept, reject, or provide you with notice when a cookie is sent. However, the Site may not function correctly if you reject cookies. We use cookies for many purposes such as to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our Site. We also use cookies to deliver content (which may include third party advertisements) specific to your interests. We do not typically save Personal Information in cookies, but we may link cookies to any information we collect.

 **Web Beacons and Other Technologies:**

The Site may also use web beacons, clear gifs, pixel tags or technologies (now or later available), which allow Sulake and third parties to monitor and collect certain information about the viewer of a web page, web-based document or message sent by the Site, such as browser type. We use the information collected though these technologies for a variety of purposes, such as to serve you relevant content and/or advertising at the Site, count Site visitors and monitor Site traffic patterns. 

**Embedded Scripts:**

Scripts and other programming code used in the Site may collect Usage Information, such as web pages visited, for how long they are visited and which links are clicked. We may use this information for a number of purposes, for example, to enhance or customize content served to users of the Site.

 **Links to Other Sites:**

The Site may contain links, including banner and other ads, to other web sites. Sulake is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. The Site may also link to web sites that feature Sulake trademarks and names along with trademarks and names of other companies. You should look at the privacy policy on that co-branded web site, as the co-branded web site may not be under Sulake's control. 

**Third Party Applications:**

Third party applications may be available via the Site. The owners of these applications (" **Third Party Owners** ") may collect your information and may have their own policies and practices. While we ask Third Party Owners to refrain from collecting your Personal Information without first obtaining your prior consent, we do not guarantee that all Third Party Owners will abide by this request. We do not screen or pre-approve Third Party Owners or their applications and we have no control over how Third Party Owners or their applications use your Personal Information. These Third Party Owners may have their own terms of service, privacy policies or other policies and ask you to agree to the same. We are not responsible for these policies or the practices of Third Party Owners. Be sure to review any available policies before submitting any Personal Information to a third party application or otherwise interacting with it.

 **Third-party Ad Serving & Audience and Traffic Measurement Services:**

The Site may use third party network advertisers to serve advertisements on the Site and may use a traffic measurement service to analyze traffic on the Site. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to the Site and other web sites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. The Site's third party ad network providers, the advertisers, the sponsors, and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies and technologies on your computer or may be given access to cookies set by the Site. These third party cookies and/or technologies may be set to, among other things, help deliver advertisements to you that you might be interested in, to prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times and to conduct research regarding the usefulness of certain advertisements to you. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with these cookies and/or technologies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities. Third party cookies, web beacons and other technologies are governed by each third party's specific privacy policy, not this one. While we may use a variety of companies to serve advertisements on the Site, you may wish to visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp, which provides information regarding the "opt-out" procedures of certain third party ad servers we may use. 

**_Who does Sulake share information with?_**

We will not share your Personal Information with third parties (aside from entities that perform services for us, such as fulfilling orders or operating our Site, that either are bound to comply with our Privacy Policy or have privacy policies that protect your information) unless you have "opted-in" to such sharing. As stated, Sulake may use third parties to accept and process orders for merchandise and products, including Habbo Coins, and to help us operate our services. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, Sulake may disclose any information you provide if required to do so by law or pursuant to a request by a law enforcement official or if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with law or with legal processes ; (2) if government authorities request it; (3) to protect and/or defend the Site's [Terms of Use](http://www.habbo.com/papers/termsAndConditions) or other Site policies such as the [Habbo Way](http://www.habbo.com/help/51); (4) protect and defend the rights or property of Sulake or third parties; or (5) act in an emergency to protect someone's safety or legal rights (" **Mandatory Disclosures** "). We may also use IP address to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies in our discretion.

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets, and, depending upon the transaction, your Personal Information may be one of the transferred assets. We may disclose and transfer Personal Information: (i) to our parent and its and our subsidiaries and affiliates; (ii) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Site, in whole or in part; or (iii) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of Sulake's stock and/or assets or other corporate change, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process; provided, however, that this Privacy Policy shall continue to govern such Personal Information (collectively and individually, (i) , (iii) are a (" **Change of Control** "). 

**_What are my options to control the use of my Personal Information?_**

 **A Special Note about Children, Childrens Privacy and Our Compliance with COPPA:**

In compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (" **COPPA** "), we do not intend to collect any Personal Information from children under thirteen (13) years of age unless we believe such collection to be permitted by law. Our Site target an audience that is over the age of thirteen (13) and some content may not be appropriate for all ages. Parental supervision is recommended. If you are the parent or guardian of a child under thirteen (13) and believe that he or she is using the Site please contact us at [privacy.us@sulake.com](mailto:privacy.us@sulake.com). Upon request, the parent or guardian of a child under thirteen (13) may review and request the deletion of such child's Personal Information, as well as refuse to permit the further collection or use of such Personal Information.

 **Opt-Out and Termination:**

We believe that our ability to share your Personal Information with certain third parties improves our ability to provide services to you. However, if you object to our sharing of your Personal Information and would like to opt-out of sharing of your Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, or if you would like to exercise your right under the CAN-SPAM Act to not receive future commercial (promotional/marketing) e-mail correspondence from us, except with respect to your prior financial transactions or communications, or as otherwise required by law, please complete and return the opt-out request available at [Opt-Out Notice](http://images.habbohotel.com/c_images/album1083/Opt_Out_Notice.pdf). Further, if you would like to terminate our use of your Personal Information on a going forward basis (except as it relates to prior transaction and communications, our record keeping and our compliance with law), there is also a place on that form to select that option. However, this may result in the termination of your Habbo user account(s).

Please note that in accordance with our routine record keeping, we may delete certain records that contain Personal Information you have submitted through the Site. We are under no obligation to store such Personal Information indefinitely and disclaim any liability arising out of, or related to, the destruction of such Personal Information. In addition, you should be aware that it is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases without some residual data because of backups and other reasons. 

**_What else should I know about my privacy?_**

 **Security:**

Sulake has security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. These include a firewall to prevent unauthorized access to our systems and maintenance of registration information in a separate database. Although we will exercise reasonable care in providing secure transmission of information between your computer and our servers, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to us over the Internet or wirelessly and we accept no liability for any unintentional disclosure. We will attempt to protect the transmission of credit card information through industry standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption. Certain aspects of the Site are not secure such as the chat areas, communities and/or other message or communication facilities and you should not disclose Personal Information or sensitive information in these non-secure areas, as Sulake cannot control third party access to or use of such information in such areas.

 **Notification of Security Breaches:**

In the unfortunate event that your "personal information" (as the term or similar terms are defined by any applicable law requiring notice upon a security breach) is compromised, we will notify as required by applicable law. If applicable law permits, you consent to notification by e-mail or by posting a notice to your user console (at Sulake's sole and absolute discretion). As such notices will be given in the most expedient time reasonable under the circumstances; provided, however, delays in notification may occur while we take necessary measures to determine the scope of the breach and restore reasonable integrity to the system as well as for the legitimate needs of law enforcement if notification would impede a criminal investigation.

 **Sulake Polls and Surveys:**

From time to time we may ask our site visitors to answer survey questions. Surveys generally deal with the Site, our products or third party products. We may ask for age or age ranges, gender, and other Usage Information. No Personal Information is shared with third parties, unless specifically disclosed at the time you participate in the survey or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. We may have agencies administering our surveys, but these agencies are acting solely on our behalf and will agree to be bound to the terms of this Privacy Policy in the same way as Sulake. We may post answers to polls or surveys at the Site, but will not include identifying information.

 **Transfer to the United States:**

The Site is operated in the United States and intended for residents of the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, be aware that information we collect will be transferred to the United States. By using the Site, accessing the Site or providing your information to the Site or Sulake, you consent to this transfer.

 **Changing Your Information and Subscriptions and Questions:**

You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of the information you submit to us, such as your contact information provided as part of registration. The Site may allow you to correct or update information you have provided to us through a Site registration form or otherwise. We will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our then active databases as soon as reasonably practicable. You may cancel or modify your subscriptions to communications from the Site by following the instructions contained within a communication you receive from the Site.

Contacting Us about Privacy Questions or Concerns:

If you have questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: privacy.us@sulake.com or send a letter to:  
Privacy Manager - habbo.com  
2101 Rosecrans Avenue, Suite 4260  
El Segundo, CA 90245

 **Privacy Policy Changes:**

We generally keep this Privacy Policy posted on the Site and you should review it frequently, as it may change from time to time without notice. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy. WHEN YOU ACCESS THE SITE, YOU AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR TO ANY CHANGES WE MAY SUBSEQUENTLY MAKE, IMMEDIATELY STOP ACCESSING THE SITE. If, at any point, we decide to use your Personal Information in a manner materially different than what was stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users of this change by e-mail to the last e-mail address provided to us. Users will have a choice (by means of an opt-in or opt-out at our discretion) as to whether or not we use their Personal Information in this different manner. We will use Personal Information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected if you opt-out of the new policy.

 **Sole Statement:**

This Privacy Policy as posted on the Site is the sole statement of our privacy policy with respect to the Site, and no summary, modification, restatement or other version thereof, or other policy statement or policy, in any form, is valid unless we post a new or revised policy to the Site.

© 2008 Sulake, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
